<?xml version="1.0"?>
<root>
  <base>
    <title>ZT400 Series Printer   </title>
    <sub_title>KEEP YOUR CRITICAL OPERATIONS RUNNING EFFICIENTLY </sub_title>
    <description>Zebra’s durable ZT400 Series printers, designed for years of performance in a wide array of applications. The ZT400 Series builds on the field-proven reliability of the Z Series™ with advancements in print speed, print quality and connectivity&#xD;
                  options.&#xD;
                </description>
    <imgs>
      <img>
        <![CDATA[/content/zebra1/us/en/vc80-spec-sheet-test/_jcr_content/mainpar/columncontrol/col1par/imagecomponent_17c7/image.adapt.full.png]]>
      </img>
    </imgs>
    <verbiage>
      <![CDATA[
                          <p>
                            Designed for ease of use, the ZT400 Series printers offer an intuitive icon-based LCD graphical user interface and easy supplies loading. And, they include standard USB, Serial, Ethernet and Bluetooth&#xAE; capabilities. Expanded RFID capacities deliver greater
                            tracking abilities, deeper visibility and enterprise insights.
                          </p>
                          <p>
                            The ZT400 Series is offered in both 4&quot; and 6&quot; models and comes standard with an extensive set of advanced features that ensure your printer investment will always meet your needs, now and in the future. Constructed using an all-metal frame and bi-fold
                            door, this printer is designed to fit well in space-constrained environments
                          </p>
                          <p>
                            Featuring Zebra&#x2019;s Link-OS&#xAE; environment &#x2014; an innovative operating system combining a powerful Multiplatform Software Development Kit (SDK) and software applications &#x2014; ZT400 Series printers are easy to integrate, manage and maintain from any location around
                            the globe.
                          </p>
                        ]]>
    </verbiage>
    <instructions>
      <title>Advanced Industrial Printing. Rugged Durability. Loaded with Features. </title>
      <content>
        <![CDATA[<p>
                            Designed to grow with your evolving business needs. The ZT400 features increased processing capabilities and an open operating architecture providing flexibility to support your ever-growing and changing application requirements
                          </p><p>
                            <b>
Application Flexibility
                            </b>
                          </p><p>
                            Expand your printing readiness through an exceptional range of media capabilities and media delivery options. Customize your printer to match your current and future business needs with end-user-installable media handling options. Standard Serial, USB,
                            Ethernet and Bluetooth features &#x2014; as well as two open media slots &#x2014; allow you to utilize non-standard connectivity options. Expanded RFID capabilities are easy to install and simple to use. Ensure quality output for small-label
                            applications with high-resolution printing capabilities.
                          </p><p>
                            <b>
Effortless to Integrate
                            </b>
                          </p><p>
                            USB host port enables simple printer configuration by easily transferring data from a USB flash drive via mirroring and expanded mapped-drive memory capabilities. Virtual Devices apps enable Link-OS printers to support wellknown legacy and competitor
                            printer languages &#x2014; in addition to ZPL&#xAE; and EPL&#x2122; &#x2014; for a future-proofed investment
                          </p><p>
                            <b>
Easy to Operate
                            </b>
                          </p><p>
                            Dynamic QR codes provide on-demand, web-based support to resolve printer errors quickly. Print Touch-enabled Link-OS printers offer web page launching features using Near Field Communication (NFC), making it easy to access Zebra&#x2019;s extensive knowledge
                            base of how-to videos and product support. Lighted media and ribbon paths make it easy to see inside the printer, even in poorly lit environments.
                          </p><p>
                            <b>
                              Simple to Manage
                            </b>
                          </p><p>
                            Zebra&#x2019;s Link-OS environment delivers enhanced capabilities to monitor, manage and maintain your printer from any location. Cloud Connect allows Link-OS printers to securely and directly interact with the Cloud for printing and device management. Profile
                            Manager enables you to edit and manage one printer, batches of printers or all Link-OS printers across your network anywhere in the world.
                          </p>]]>
      </content>
    </instructions>
    <contact_footer>
      <code>VC80</code>
      <one_line_desc>PUT REAL DESKTOP POWER IN YOUR WAREHOUSE VEHICLES WITH THE VC80. </one_line_desc>
    </contact_footer>
  </base>
  <service>
    <title>&#xD;
                                ZebraCare Services&#xD;
                                &#xD;
                              </title>
    <content>&#xD;
                                Increase printer uptime and reduce lost productivity and unbudgeted repair costs by selecting a ZebraCare service agreement. A cost-effective means of planning and budgeting for your annual maintenance expenditures, your agreement ensures that trained&#xD;
                                Zebra® technicians will bring your printer back to factory specifications. Zebra offers a variety of plans to fit your budget and business needs.&#xD;
&#xD;
                              </content>
  </service>
  <supplies>
    <title>&#xD;
                                Genuine Zebra™ Supplies&#xD;
                                &#xD;
                              </title>
    <content>&#xD;
                                As one of the largest thermal supplies manufacturers in North America, Zebra provides convenient shipping throughout the region via our four manufacturing locations. Zebra provides high-quality supplies solutions for virtually any application: • The largest&#xD;
                                selection of pre-tested, labels, tags and ribbons for your ZT400 printer. • Ability to create custom labels in any size with pre-printed text, graphics and logos. • Supplies extensively tested to ensure print quality, chemical&#xD;
                                resistance and adhesive strength. • ISO 9001: 2008 certified&#xD;
&#xD;
                              </content>
  </supplies>
  <specs>
    <title>ZT400 Specifications</title>
    <sub_title/>
    <parameters>
      <parameter>
        <caption/>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                  Printer Name&#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  ZT410&#xD;
                                   ZT420&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>STANDARD FEATURES</caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  Print Methods: Thermal transfer and direct thermal printing Construction: Metal frame and bi-fold metal media cover with enlarged clear viewing window Side-loading supplies path for simplified media and ribbon loading Element Energy Equalizer™ (E3™) for&#xD;
                                  superior print quality Communications: USB 2.0, high-speed, RS-232 Serial, 10/100 Ethernet, Bluetooth 2.1, USB Host Back-lit, multiline graphic LCD display with intuitive menu and easy-touse keypad for quick operation&#xD;
                                  Bi-colored status LEDs for quick printer status ENERGY STAR® qualified&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>PRINTER SPECIFICATIONS</caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                  Resolution&#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
203 dpi/8 dots per mm&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                  &#xD;
300 dpi/12 dots per mm (optional)&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                  &#xD;
 600 dpi/24 dots per mm (optional for ZT410 only)&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Memory </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                    256 MB SDRAM memory&#xD;
&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                    512 MB on-board linear Flash memory&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Maximum Print Width</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                    4.09"/104 mm (ZT410)&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                    6.6"/168 mm (ZT420)&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Maximum Print Speed</name>
            <value>&#xD;
14 ips/356 mm per second&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                  Media Sensors&#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                   Dual media sensors: transmissive and reflective&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Media Characteristics</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                    Media web width (label and liner): ZT410 • 1.00"/25.4 mm to 4.5"/114 mm tear/cutter • 1.00"/25.4 mm to 4.25"/108 mm peel/rewind ZT420 • 2.00"/51 mm to 7.0"/178 mm tear/cutter • 2.00"/51 mm to 6.75"/171 mm peel/rewind Maximum non-continuous label length: 39"/991 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Print Length</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  ZT410 • 203 dpi: 157"/3988 mm • 300 dpi: 73"/1854 mm • 600 dpi: 39"/991 mm ZT420 • 203 dpi: 102"/2591 mm • 300 dpi: 45"/1143 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Maximum Media Roll Size</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  8.0"/203 mm O.D. on a 3"/76 mm I.D. core&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Media Thickness</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  0.0023"/0.058 mm to 0.010"/0.25 mm&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Media Types</name>
            <value>Continuous, die-cut, notch, black-mark </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Ribbon Characteristics</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                      (Thermal-transfer option only)&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Outside Diameter</name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                450 m: 3.2"/81.3 mm O.D. on a 1.0"/25.4 mm I.D. core&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
Standard Length&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
1476'/450 m&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
Width&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  ZT410 - 2.00"/51 mm to 4.33"/110 mm ZT420 - 2.00"/51 mm to 6.85"/174 mm&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
Ribbon Setup&#xD;
                                  &#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  Ribbon wound ink-side out; ribbon wound ink-side in can be used with the optional ribbon spindle&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>OPERATING CHARACTERISTICS </caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>Environmental </name>
            <value> Operating Environment: • Thermal transfer: 40º to 104ºF/5º to 40ºC • Thermal direct: 32º to 104ºF/0º to 40ºC • 20% to 85% non-condensing R.H. Storage/Transportation Environment: • -40º to 140ºF/-40º to 60ºC • 5% to 85% non-condensing R.H</value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Electrical </name>
            <value>Auto-detectable (PFC Compliant) 100-240VAC, 50-60Hz, rated at 100 Watts ENERGY STAR qualified&#xD;
</value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Agency Approvals</name>
            <value>IEC 60950, EN 55022 Class B, EN 55024, EN 61000-3-2, EN 61000-3-3 cTUVus, CE Marking, FCC-B, ICES-003, VCCI, C-Tick, NOM, S-Mark (Arg), CCC, CU, BSMI, KCC, SABS, IN-Metro&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS</caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>ZT410 closed</name>
            <value> Width: 10.6"/269 mm Height: 12.75"/324 mm Depth: 19.50"/495 mm Weight: 36 lb./16.33Kg&#xD;
</value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>ZT420 closed&#xD;
                                </name>
            <value> Width: 13.25"/336.55 mm Height: 12.75"/324 mm Depth: 19.50"/495 mm Weight: 40 lb./18.14 Kg </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>OPTIONS AND ACCESSORIES</caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>Communication </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  Parallel (Bi-directional interface) Wireless: ZebraNet® Printer Server — supports 802.11 a/b/g/n networks via an internally integrated option that enables the use of Webview and  Alert features&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Media Handling </name>
            <value>Rewind: Internally rewinds a full roll of printed labels on 3" core, or peels and rewinds liner (Factory installed only) Peel: Front-mount, passive peel option Peel: Liner take-up option — additional full-roll liner take-up spindle accommodates standard printer base Cutter: Front-mount guillotine cutter and catch tray 1" I.D. Core media supply hanger Ink-side in ribbon supply spindle&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>RFID </name>
            <value> Supports tags compatible with UHF EPC Gen 2 V1.2/ISO 18000-6C Integrated RFID system is user-upgradable in  the field and available on both 4" and 6" models Adaptive Encoding Technology automatically selects optimum encode settings </value>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Keyboard Display Unit </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  Supports KDU Plus™ and ZKDU: Enter  variable data and retrieve stored forms  for standalone applications&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>LINK-OS SOLUTIONS</caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>Software Tools </name>
            <value>Document Design: Quickly design a customized print solution using your business data and Zebra’s intuitive, plug-and-print design tools. Device Integration: Zebra offers apps and products designed to help you integrate Zebra devices into your existing systems Device Management: Manage your print operations locally and globally with Zebra’s suite of device management tools. Developer Tools: Provides you the tools you need to create your own apps, including documentation, source code, programming languages, templates and more. </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>FIRMWARE&#xD;
</caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>Resident ZPL, ZPL II® and EPL† programming languages, selectable through software or front panel. XML-enabled Printing — allows XML communications for barcode label printing.&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>BARCODE SYMBOLOGIES </caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name> </name>
            <value>Linear Barcodes: Code 11, Code 39, Code 93, Code 128 with subsets A/B/C and UCC Case Codes, ISBT-128, UPC-A, UPC-E, EAN-8, EAN-13, UPC and EAN 2- or 5-digit extensions, Plessey, Postnet, Standard 2-of-5, Industrial 2-of-5, Interleaved 2-of-5, Logmars, MSI, Codabar, Planet Code 2-Dimensional Barcodes: Codablock, PDF417, Code 49, DataMatrix, MaxiCode, QR Code, TLC 39, MicroPDF, RSS-14 (and composite), Aztec&#xD;
                                  </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
      <parameter>
        <caption>&#xD;
                              FONTS AND GRAPHICS&#xD;
                            </caption>
        <items>
          <item>
            <name>&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </name>
            <value>&#xD;
                                  16 resident expandable ZPL II bitmap and two resident scalable ZPL fonts Asian and other international scalable and smooth bitmapped fonts Unicode: For multi-language printing Downloadable objects include graphics, scalable and bitmap fonts, label templates and formats IBM Code Page 850 international character sets are available in the fonts A, B, C, D, E, F, G and 0 through software control Code Page 1250, 1252, 1253, 1254, 1255 Support with font 0 64 MB user available non-volatile memory storage for downloadable objects 4 MB user-available SDRAM&#xD;
&#xD;
                                </value>
          </item>
        </items>
      </parameter>
    </parameters>
  </specs>
</root>